tricycle.org 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy - Tricycle: The Buddhist Review

Tricycle.org respects our users and their privacy.  The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the following:    

  * What we do with the data collected
  * For what purposes we will use it
  * How long we keep it
  * With whom we share it, and
  * Under what terms.

Our Privacy Policy covers all of Tricycle.org and the following content and brands:  Tricycle: The Buddhist Review; Tricycle magazine; Tricycle Dharma Talks series; Tricycle Tours; Tricycle Online Courses; and other related properties owned or controlled by Tricycle.  Our Privacy Policy does not apply to entities not owned or controlled by us, such as third-party applications and/or other web sites.

The Privacy Policy covers information users provide to us, including, but not limited to, name, email address, physical address, phone number, other personal information, content of messages and comments, and transactional information, including but not limited to, credit card and billing data.  Information collected from users may include their site activity, access device, browser type, their location, IP address, pages visited,  cookies, and other similar information.

We use the Information Covered to manage services provided by us or our licensees or affiliates, such as contacting users and for advertising and marketing purposes. We may share non-personally identifiable information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties.  We keep such information for only as long as needed for business operations and legal compliance.

We use Google Analytics’ 3rd-party audience data such as age, gender and interests to better understanding the behavior of our customers and work with companies that collect information about your online activities to provide advertising targeted to suit your interests and preferences. For example, you may see certain ads on this website or other websites because we contract with Google and other similar companies to target our ads based on information we or they have collected, including information that was collected through automated means (such as cookies and web beacons). These companies also use automated technologies to collect information when you click on our ads, which helps track and manage the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.

You may opt out of the automated collection of information by third-party ad networks for the purpose of delivering advertisements tailored to your interests, by visiting the consumer opt-out page for the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> and edit or opt-out your Google Display Network ads’ preferences at [http://www.google.com/ads/preferences](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). Because those opt-out and preference control pages are specific to the individual browser used to visit it, and because that page is not operated by us, we are unable to perform the opt-outs on your behalf.

Cookies are small pieces of information sent by a website to a user’s hard disk. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. By continuing to visit our web and mobile sites, you agree to the placement of cookies on your device. If you choose not to accept our cookies, we cannot guarantee that your experience will be as fulfilling as it would otherwise be. We may also place cookies from third parties for functional and marketing purposes. The use of cookies is widespread and benefits the user.

Tricycle.org may disclose information pursuant to subpoenas, court orders, or other requests (including criminal and civil matters) required from jurisdictions inside or outside of the United States where we have a good faith belief that the response is required under local laws of that jurisdiction, applies to users from that jurisdiction, and is consistent with generally accepted international standards.  We may also share information when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activity, to prevent imminent bodily harm, or to protect ourselves and you from people violating our Terms of Service.  This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, courts or other government entities.

We take many steps to keep your information secure.   All account information is stored on secured servers behind firewalls.  Sensitive information (such as credit card numbers and passwords), is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL).  Despite our best efforts, there are risks inherent in sharing information. We cannot control actions of other users with whom you share your information. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information.  We cannot ensure that information you share will not become publicly available.  We are not responsible for third party circumvention of privacy settings or security measures.

To further protect your information, you can reduce your risk by using security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up-to-date antivirus software. Also, you can report any security violations to us at [support@tricycle.org](mailto:support@tricycle.com). 

We also respect minors’ privacy. Tricycle.org is intended for adults. Children under age 13 are not permitted to join this site.  We also recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information.

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a “Promotion”) through the site that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to the terms, conditions or official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s official rules such as on a winners list.

Tricycle.org reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy. Tricycle.org will not, however, use your Personal Information without your consent in a manner materially different from what was stated at the time it was collected.

This privacy policy and the interpretation of this privacy policy will be governed by and construed under the laws of the state of New York, without regard to its conflicts of laws principles, and will specifically not be governed by the United Nations conventions on contracts for the international sale of goods, if otherwise applicable. By using the site, you agree that jurisdiction over and venue in any legal proceeding directly or indirectly arising out of or relating to the site, the use or access thereof, or this privacy policy shall be in the applicable state or federal courts located in New York, NY. You hereby consent and submit to the exclusive personal jurisdiction and venue of the applicable federal and state courts located in New York, NY for any such legal proceeding. You agree that any cause of action or claim you may have with respect to the site must be commenced within one year after such claim or cause of action arises or else you agree you have waived any such claim.

For questions or concerns about our privacy policy, or to request the removal of, or a change to, your personal information, contact us at [support@tricycle.org](mailto:support@tricycle.com).

_Effective: May 25, 2018_
